#### Contact

deborahmarie@earthlink.net

www.linkedin.com/in/debbie-ebertmsn-rn-nea-bc-cnor-ccrn-cpancapa-9590b729 (LinkedIn) memorialcare.org (Company)

### Top Skills

Healthcare

Surgery

Critical Care

## Languages

French

**English** 

#### Certifications

Certified Nurse Operating Room Nationally Certified Perianesthesia Nurse

Critical Care Registered Nurse ACLS

Nurse Executive

#### Honors-Awards

World Class Leader Award AORN Achievement Award for Nursing

Honor Society of Nursing
Woman of the Year Award

# Debbie Ebert, MSN, RN, NEA-BC, CNOR, CCRN, CPAN, CAPA

Vice President Perioperative Services at Memorial Care Health System

Greater Los Angeles Area

# Summary

Proven leadership with emphasis on operational and clinical excellence through professional development and strategic planning. Over 35 years experience in perioperative and critical care nursing. Certified Nurse Executive by ANCC. National Certification in Operating Room, PeriAnesthesia, Critical Care, Surgical Services Management & Healthcare Finance. Member Nursing Honor Society, Sigma Theta Tau International. World Class Leader Award Recipient MemorialCare Health System 2018. AORN National Recruitment and Retention Task Force Chair 2019-2020 & 20-21, Pfiedler Board of Directors, CCI Recertification Committee 2019-2020, President AORN Chapter 2902, 2013-2014. Extensive management skills in health care settings. An advocate for Nursing Excellence, speaking nationally on safe perioperative care and professionalism. Licensed in California, Nevada, Florida and Georgia.

Specialties: Leadership, Surgery and PeriAnesthesia, Professional Development and Training, PeriOperative Services Management, Strategic Planning and Innovation, Health Care Finance, Infection Control, Quality, Safety and Quality Assurance.

# Experience

MemorialCare
Vice President Perioperative Services
March 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

Responsible for providing system-wide strategic direction and senior leadership for Perioperative Services. Works collaboratively with Senior

Leaders across MemorialCare Health System to develop and implement strategic and operational initiatives for Perioperative Services.

MemorialCare Long Beach Medical Center 2 years 7 months

Executive Director Perioperative Services November 2017 - Present (2 years 7 months) Long Beach, CA

Responsible for services across multiple campuses including Long Beach Memorial and Miller Children's and Women's hospitals. Responsibility extends to PeriAnesthesia Departments, Surgical Scheduling, Endoscopy Services, Business Operations and Sterile Processing. 24/7 responsibility to develop strategies which align with mission, vision and values of the organization. Provides oversight for areas of responsibility to ensure achievement of goals for the departments. Serves in a clinically integrated organization leading 44 Operating Rooms and 431 FTEs in Level II Trauma Magnet facilities. Reports to COO.

Vice President Perioperative Services November 2017 - Present (2 years 7 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

BayCare Health System
Director of Surgical Services
February 2015 - November 2017 (2 years 10 months)
Tampa, Florida

Leader in strategic planning with focus on business development and service line growth. Responsible for daily operations, productivity and budget of Operating Room, Anesthesia, Sterile Processing, PACU, ASU, Preassessment and Endoscopy. Champion best practices through collaboration with Perioperative Council. Active leader in process improvement projects and professional development of team members. Director Surgical Services Education Collaborative and Periop 101 Internship Program. Reports to President of Morton Plant North Bay.

University Medical Center of Southern Nevada 2 years 6 months Director (Interim) of Surgical Services August 2014 - January 2015 (6 months) University Medical Center of Southern Nevada Served as Interim Surgical Services Director in a Level 1 Trauma Center and University teaching hospital with responsibility for global operations of the Department. Responsible for oversight of all aspects of Surgical Services with major responsibility for budget and productivity as well as supervision and performance evaluation of 240 FTEs.

Also continued in the role of Clinical Manager roles of both OR and PACU/ ASU positions while assuming Director responsibilities. Worked collaboratively with OR Business Manager and Sterile Processing Manager to facilitate fiscal responsibility, efficiency, quality and safety.

Interfaced with all hospital departments. Served as Surgical Team Leader to launch first robotic surgery program in the institution.

Served as active participant in strategic planning for the department and organization. Reported to CNO and COO.

Clinical Manager of Surgical Services August 2012 - January 2015 (2 years 6 months)

Las Vegas, Nevada

Responsible for administrative, clinical, fiscal and human resources management of the periOperative department in a large acute care Level 1 University teaching hospital; 26 ORs;1500+ cases/mo;210 FTEs. Responsible for training, supervision and performance evaluation of staff OR, PACU, ASU, Anesthesia and Pre-assessment (PAT). Provided leadership in the setting of department budget, monitoring of compliance with standards and strategic planning.

Served on Surgery, Anesthesia Services, Safety, Quality, Value Analysis, Trauma, Infection Prevention, SUSP and Emergency Preparedness Committees.

Championed and served as Project Lead for the Surgical Unit Safety Project (SUSP) in conjunction with Johns Hopkins University and presented a national videoconference in December 2013.

Enhanced periOperative normothermia initiative to meet standard and best practices.

Created content and collaborated in development of surgical services webpage design.

Centennial Surgery 5 years 11 months

PeriOperative Consultant August 2012 - October 2014 (2 years 3 months) Las Vegas, NV Provide consulting services for perioperative policy and procedures to promote evidence-based practice and insure compliance. Serve on Executive and Safety Committee. Project leader for AAAHC compliance, quality improvement projects and re-survey process. October 1, 2014- Contract changed per my request to fee for service for future needs.

Administrator/Clinical Director December 2008 - August 2012 (3 years 9 months) Las Vegas, Nevada

Responsible for all surgical services processes including staffing, compliance, safety, pharmacy, lab, sterile processing, materials management, evidence-based practice, education/in-service, professional development, and physician relations. Director of Nursing. Job description transitioned to Consultant for Peri-operative services to accommodate my new position at University Medical Center.

Centennial Hills Hospital ICU ICU/CCU RN/Rapid Response Team December 2008 - May 2009 (6 months) Las Vegas, Nevada

Critical Care RN ICU/CCU and Rapid Response Team. Per diem contract for specified period to achieve hours required for CCRN recertification.

American Nursing Services, Inc.
Critical Care Nurse ICU/CCU Specialty
December 2006 - December 2008 (2 years 1 month)
Las Vegas, Nevada

Travel RN in critical care/peri-op units as well as Child Haven Medical Unit in Clark County NV.

Las Vegas Plastic SurgeryLas Veg Administrator/Director of Nursing March 1984 - December 2006 (22 years 10 months) Las Vegas, Nevada

Member of planning and building committee for new facility. Served as Director of Nursing and Surgical Services. Author of policy and procedures, compliance officer, and training preceptor for professional staff. Member of Executive Committee.

Providence Hospital Mobile Staff/Charge RN OR, Staff RN CCU/ICU June 1978 - March 1984 (5 years 10 months)

Operating Room & Critical Care Units

Surgery staff and charge nurse 5 days/wk. Scrubbed and circulated all specialty lines. Served as charge nurse. Augmented nursing knowledge base and skill set by training and working in CCU/ICU 3-11 shift 2 days/week.

## Education

Sacred Heart University
MSN, Nursing Leadership/Administration · (2012 - 2014)

Adventist University of Health Sciences
Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing, Nursing Administration, Nursing
Research and Clinical Nursing · (2010 - 2012)

Providence School of Nursing RN, Nursing · (1975 - 1978)

Spring Hill College RN, Nursing · (1975 - 1976)